Preliminary Inventory to the Russia. Legatsiia (Württemberg, Germany) Records, 1828-1904
Hoover Institution Archives
Russia. Legatsiia (Württemberg, Germany) Records,
1828-1904
28011
Russia. Legatsiia (Württemberg, Germany)
16 manuscript boxes (6.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, orders, memoranda, and notes, relating to Russian-Württemberg relations
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1928
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Germany; Germany--Foreign relations--Russia; Russia; Russia--Foreign relations--Germany; Russia--Foreign relations--Württemberg (Germany); Württemberg (Germany); Württemberg (Germany)--Foreign relations--Russia
Container List
- Communications of the Minister of Foreign Affairs on political questions and instructions to Mr. D'Obreskoff, Minister in Stuttgart (Box 1)
  - 1828-1830
  - 1831-32
- Communications of the Minister of Foreign Affairs addressed to Minister Baron Meyendorf and to the Charge d'Affaires Mr. de Stoffregen and Count de Medem, 1833-1840
- Political reports of Russian Minister in Stuttgart Prince Gortchakoff addressed to the Russian Chancellor Count Nesselrode
  - 1840: Nos. 1-28, 2-34
  - 1841: Nos. 1-44
  - 1842: Nos. 1-8, 1-23
  - 1843: Nos. 24-52
- Political reports of Rusian Minister in Stuttgart Prince Gortchakoff addressed to the Russian Chancellor Count Nesselrode and Count Worontzoff-Dachkoff (Box 2)
  - 1844: Nos. 53-80
  - 1845: Nos. 81-177
  - 1846: Nos. 118-183 (from Stuttgart and Baden, private letters on political questions)
  - 1847: Nos. 184-228 (from Stuttgart, private letters)
  - 1848:
    - January-June, Nos. 229-314 (private letters)
    - July-December, Nos. 315-392
  - 1849: Nos. 393-439 (Box 3)
  - 1850: Nos. 440-519 (some addressed to Mr. Seniavin)
- Political reports of Prince Gortchakoff, Minister to the Germanic Confederation, from Frankfurt on the Main
  - 1851: Nos. 50-75
  - 1852: Nos. 76-107
  - 1853: Nos. 108-112
- Political reports of Prince Gortchakoff, Minister to the Germanic Confederation, from Stuttgart (Box 4)
  - 1851: Nos. 520-562 (No. 524 missing)
  - 1852: Nos. 563-616 (includes private letters)
  - 1853: Nos. 617-652
  - 1854: Nos. 653-694
- Circulars, communications and instructions of the Minister for Foreign Affairs relating to political questions to Prince Gortchakoff and Charge d'Affaires in Stuttgart, 1850-1853
- Special mission of Prince Gortchakoff in Vienna, 1854, and the Vienna Conference of 1855-56 (Box 5)
- Vienna Conference, 1855-56, correspondence and documents, deposited by Prince Gortchakoff
- Reports of Mr. de Stoffregen, Charge d'Affaires in Stuttgart, addressed to the Minister for Foreign Affairs during the absence of the Head of the Legation
  - 1848-49: Nos. 1-68
  - 1849-1850: Nos. 69-123 (No. 105 is missing)
  - 1850-55: Nos. 125-201
- Political reports to St. Petersburg of Mr. de Glinka, Charge d'Affaires to the Germanic Confederation in Frankfurt, 1850-54
- Correspondence between Prince Gortchakoff, Stuttgart, and Mr. de Glinka, Franfurt on the Main, 1950-52
- Political reports of Mr. Titoff, Minister Ad Interim in Stuttgart, 1854-55: Nos. 695-730 (Box 6)
- Letters of Mr. Titoff to Count Nesselrode, 1854-55
- Correspondence and documents of Mr. Titoff, Second Russian Plenipotentiary at the Vienna Conference and Minister Ad Interim at Stuttgart
  - 1854-55
  - 1856
  - 1854-58
- Reports and private letters of Mr. Titoff and Mr. Stoffregen, 1855-56: Nos. 1-16
- Reports and private letters of Mr. Stoffregen to St. Petersburg, 1856: Nos. 17-37
- Reports and private letters of Count Benckendorf, Minister at Stuttgart, and Mr. Stoffregen addressed to Prince Gortchakoff in St. Petersburg, 1856-58: Nos. 1-68
- Reports and private letter of Mr. Titoff (Box 7)
  - 1858-59: Nos. 69-96
  - 1860-62: Nos. 97-148
  - 1853-65: Nos. 149-169
- Correspondence of Russian Representatives in Stuttgart with Russian Representatives in other countries
  - Vienna, 1850-56
  - Munich, 1850-58
  - Berlin, 1850-58
  - Frankfurt on the Main, 1850-57
  - Paris, 1856-58
  - Miscellaneous, 1858-1864
- Communications and instructions by Count Nesselrode to Mr. Titoff, 1854-55 (Box 8)
- Communications and instructions by Count Nesselrode and Prince Gortchakoff to Mr. Titoff and Mr. de Stoffregen, 1856
- Communications and instrutions of Prince Gortchakoff
  - 1857-59
  - 1860
  - 1861-65
- Correspondence and notes of Mr. Titoff, 1860-62
- Confidential letters of Count Nesselrode to Prince Gortchakoff in Vienna, 1855-56 (Box 9)
- Letters of Prince Gortchakoff to Count Chreptovitch, Ambassador in London, 1856
- Agreement of Navigation on the Danube, correspondence and documents pertaining to, 1857-58
- Political reports of Russian Representatives in various countries to the Minister in Stuttgart
  - 1859
    - January-February
    - February-March
    - March-April
    - April-July
  - 1860 (Box 10)
  - 1861
  - 1862
    - January-May
    - May-December
  - 1863
  - 1864
  - 1865 (Box 11)
- Correspondence with the Diplomatic Chancery of His Majesty's Lieutenant-Governor in Warsaw
  - 1842-1860
  - 1861-68
- Correspondence pertaining to Polish affairs, 1862-64
- Memorandum to Alexander II from Grand Duke Konstantin Nikolaevich, Lieutenant-Governor of Poland, September 5/17, 1862
- Survey on the administration of Poland, 1855-1862
- Polish Insurrection of 1863, telegrams from Warsaw
- Tengoborsky, Diplomatic Chancery in Warsaw, reports of, July 1862 to November 1863
- Tengoborsky, Diplomatic Chancery in Warsaw, reports of, July 1862 to November 1863 (Box 12)
- Benckendorf, Count
  - Correspondence, 1847-1858
  - Manuscript drafts, 1848-1856
  - Notes and manuscript drafts pertaining to military
  - questions
  - Memoirs
  - The History of the Caucasian Campaign of 1845 (Box 13)
- Russian Army
- Benckendorf, Count
  - Correspondence
    - 1848-1856
    - 1852, 1854-55 (acquisition of gun powders and munitions)
  - Special mission to Spain, 1856
  - Private correspondence
- Royal Foreign Office of Wuerttemberg, notes (Box 14)
  - 1835-38
  - 1839-1846
  - 1847-1857
  - 1857-1863 (Box 15)
  - 1864-69
- Royal Foreign Office of Wuerttemberg, notes of Russian Representatives
  - 1835-1841
  - 1842-46
  - 1847-1850
  - 1850-52
  - 1853-1856 (Box 16)
  - 1857-1863
  - 1864-69
- Maria Aleksandrovna, Empress, journey abroad, 1871
- Vera Konstantinovna, Grand Duchess, project of marriage contract to Duke Wilhelm of Wuerttemberg
- Alexander II, journeys abroad
  - 1873
  - 1874
- Vera Konstantinovna, Grand Duchess, wedding festivities plans to Duke Wilhelm of Wuerttemberg
- Instructions for the Russian Army Respecting the Laws and Customs of War on Land, sanctioned in July 1904
- Passports for Russian subjects